MoMA PS1 Archives
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series I: Curatorial and Exhibition Records, (19682009)
  - Subseries I.A: General Files, (19702009)
    - "Sound '79 Sunday Performance Series: Yosunao Tone October 28", 1979; Sunday Performance Series(October 7-November 18, 1979): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 15, Folder I.A.348)
    - "Sound '79 Sunday Performance Series: Richard Teitelbaum October 14", 1979; Sunday Performance Series(October 7-November 18, 1979): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 15, Folder I.A.349)
    - "Sound '79 Special Projects: Mimi Smith", 1979; Special Projects (Fall 1979):Sound(September 30-November 18, 1979): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 15, Folder I.A.350)
    - "Sound '79 Special Projects: Anna Lockwood", 1979; Special Projects (Fall 1979):Sound(September 30-November 18, 1979): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 15, Folder I.A.351)
    - "Sound '79: Meet the Composer", 1977-1978; Various materials and correspondence related to the activities at P.S. 1 funded by "Meet the Composer" grants; no material specifically related to 1979 activities present. Special Projects (Winter 1977-1978) (December 3, 1977-January 29, 1978): Printed Ephemera (Box 15, Folder I.A.352)
    - "Sound '79: Meet the Composer Funding", 1979; Correspondence, funding contracts, and other materials, with schedules of performances. Sunday Performance Series(October 7-November 18, 1979): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 15, Folder I.A.353)
    - "Sound '79: Disbursements (Including Artist' Checks and Advertising)", 1979; Includes schedules of films and performances, with other documents. Sunday Film and Video Presentations(September 30-November 18, 1979): General Exhibition Documentation Sunday Performance Series(October 7-November 18, 1979): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 15, Folder I.A.354)
    - "Sound '79: Radio Publicity", 1979; Sent correspondence. Sound(September 30-November 18, 1979): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 15, Folder I.A.355)
    - "Sound '79: Fund Raising", 1979; Correspondence, with some budget and other documents. Sound(September 30-November 18, 1979): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 15, Folder I.A.356)
    - "Sound '79 Scores and Notations: Peter Frank", 1979; includes notes on participants and essay text by Frank. Sound(September 30-November 18, 1979): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 15, Folder I.A.357)
    - "Sound '79: Press Reviews", 1979; Once clipping only, by John Perrault. Sound(September 30-November 18, 1979): News Clippings (Box 15, Folder I.A.358)
    - "Sound Shows", 1979; Press releases with two slides of installations. Sound(September 30-November 18, 1979): Installation Photographs (Box 15, Folder I.A.359)
    - Frederick Spratt, 1979; Includes installation photographs, slides submitted as a proposal for the exhibition, correspondence, and press material. Frederick Spratt: Ganko(October 24-November 17, 1979): Press Release; Installation Photographs; Printed Ephemera; Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 15, Folder I.A.360)
    - Sean Scully, 1979; Includes checklist and draft (by the artist) and final press release with other materials. Sean Scully: Paintings,1975-1979(November 28-December 22, 1979): Checklist; Press Release; Art and Event Photographs (Box 15, Folder I.A.361)
    - Merrill Wagner, 1979; Checklist, background materials, press release and contract. Merrill Wagner(November 28-December 22, 1979): Checklist; Press Release (Box 15, Folder I.A.362)
    - Artists Stamps and Stamp Images, 1979; Includes one installation photograph with other contact sheet images, press release, crate and insurance lists, partial checklists, with unbound catalogue pages. Artists' Stamps and Stamp Images(December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Printed Ephemera; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.363)
    - Artists Stamps and Stamp Images, 1979; One presumably complete copy of the ring-bound catalogue published by the Simon Fraser University, Burnaby, British Artists' Stamps and Stamp Images(December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Printed Ephemera (Box 16, Folder I.A.364)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980): Arthur Weyhe, Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980) (December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.365)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980): Irene Whittome, Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980) (December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.366)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980): John Willenbacher, As correspondence indicates, Willenbacher's installation was extended over two special project periods. Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980) (December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.367)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980): Kent Floeter, Background materials and images of previous installations, as well as installation photographs at P.S. 1. Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980) (December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Installation Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 716, Folder I.A.368*)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980): Wayne Hazen, Includes background material, contract, and photographs of proposed installation. Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980) (December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.369)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980): Bruce Chao, Includes project proposal, artist's statement, installation photograph and images of previous installations of the work. Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980) (December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Installation Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.370)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980): Jennifer Cecere, Includes background materials and artwork and installation photographs,. Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980) (December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Installation Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.371)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980): Bruce Cunningham, Includes handwritten and typescript project descriptions, some correspondence, with installation photographs. Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980) (December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Installation Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.372)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980): Esti Schur, Includes correspondence and artist's statement. Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980) (December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.373)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980): Raquel Rabinovich, Includes installation description, photographs of previous works, and background information. Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980) (December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.374)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980): Craig Stockwell, Includes installation proposal, installation photographs, with other documents. Special Projects (Winter 1979-1980) (December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Installation Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.375)
    - Film (Winter 1979-1980): Dara Birnbaum, Film (Winter 1979-1980):Dara Birnbaum: "Kiss The Girls: Make Them Cry"(December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Press Release; Printed Ephemera; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.376)
    - Architecture (Winter 1979-1980): Friday Architects, Architecture (Winter 1979-1980):Friday Architects: "Projective Images"(December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Printed Ephemera; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.377)
    - Multidisciplinary Program, Architecture: "Design Arts Grant Application Supplementary Material", 1980; Large amount of photocopies of exhibition images, with documents on exhibition participants and curators. (Box 16, Folder I.A.378)
    - Poetry (Winter 1979-1980): Frank Moore and Brad Gooch, Poetry (Winter 1979-1980):Brad Gooch and Frank Moore(December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.379)
    - Multidisciplinary Program, Poetry: "Room 203 Ann Lauterbach Curator", 1980; Materials on the specific room used for poetry readings and the curator of many of those programs. (Box 16, Folder I.A.380)
    - Multidisciplinary Program, Poetry: "NYSCA Files and General Description", 1978-1980; Materials describing the program, with some correspondence. (Box 16, Folder I.A.381)
    - "Sound: Project Description and Applications", 1980; Budget materials and grant applications describing the Fall-Spring sound program schedule. (Box 16, Folder I.A.382)
    - Sound (Winter 1979-1980): Julie Wachtel, Includes project proposal, contract, and photograph. Sound (Winter 1979-1980):Julie Wachtel: Follow the Leader(December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Installation Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 16, Folder I.A.383)
    - Image and Object in Contemporary Sculpture, 1979-1980; Includes floor plan and poster of season's exhibitions, with press release and checklist of Image and Object…. Image and Object in Contemporary Sculpture(December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Checklist; Press Release (Box 16, Folder I.A.384)
    - "Image and Object in Contemporary Sculpture: Detroit Institute of the Arts", 1979-1980; Correspondence regarding the exhibition agreement, transport and installation of artworks travelling from Detroit. Image and Object in Contemporary Sculpture(December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.385)
    - "Image and Object in Contemporary Sculpture: Michigan Press Reviews", 1979-1980; Press reviews from the Detroit instantiation of the exhibition. Image and Object in Contemporary Sculpture(December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): News Clippings (Box 17, Folder I.A.386)
    - "Image and Object in Contemporary Sculpture: Disbursements", 1979-1980; Two pieces of correspondence and list of installation costs for the exhibition. Image and Object in Contemporary Sculpture(December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.387)
    - Image and Object in Contemporary Sculpture: Catalogue and Detroit Installation Photographs, 1979; Includes catalogue and contact sheets of installation photographs from Detroit. Image and Object in Contemporary Sculpture(December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Printed Ephemera; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.388)
    - Image and Object in Contemporary Sculpture: Detroit Installation Photographs, 1979; Numerous photographs of artworks and installation views from Detroit. Image and Object in Contemporary Sculpture(December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Art and Event Photographs (Box 17, Folder I.A.389)
    - "Dance and Performance Proposals: Fall 1980", 1979-1982; Applications, project proposals, and funding documents, with some correspondence. (Box 17, Folder I.A.390)
    - "Dance and Performance Proposals: Ann Wilson (Pending)", 1979; Project descriptions and proposals from the artist. (Box 17, Folder I.A.391)
    - "Dance and Performance Proposals: Diane Jacobowitz", 1980; Project proposal and correspondence. (Box 17, Folder I.A.392)
    - "Dance and Performance Proposals: Martha Rienzi", 1979 (Box 17, Folder I.A.393)
    - "Dance and Performance Proposals: Rosalind Newman", 1979 (Box 17, Folder I.A.394)
    - "Dance and Performance Proposals: Joseph Dunn; Melissa Fenley", 1978-1980 (Box 17, Folder I.A.395)
    - "Dance and Performance: Min Tanaka", 1978; Includes brochures on Tanaka, notes, and advertisements. Min Tanaka: Hyperdance-Drive Series(November 24-November 26, 1978): News Clippings; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.396)
    - Dance Materials, 1979-1985; Includes applications and description for the Summer Dance Residency Program, press photos for Tom Brazil's 1985 exhibition of dance photography, and news clippings and ephemera relating to various dance programs. Spring Dance Series (1984):Frontline: Dance and Social Commentary(April 28-June 10, 1984): Printed Ephemera (Box 17, Folder I.A.397)
    - Ellen Phelan, 1980; Contract, photographs, and CV. Ellen Phelan(January 9-February 2, 1980): Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.398)
    - Dimitry Marinoff, 1980; Contract and CV only. Dimitry Merinoff: Paintings 1950-1970(January 9-February 2, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.399)
    - Royden Rabinowitch, 1980; Contract and one piece of correspondence. Royden Rabinowitch(February 13-March 8, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.400)
    - Glenda Hydler, 1980; Includes signed and numbered artists' book by Hydler:The Human Dilemma, Part I, artist's statement, lists of books by the artist, background information, and draft press release. Glenda Hydler: "In Reverence: Books and Other Work"(February 13-March 8, 1980): Press Release; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.401)
    - Poetry (Winter 1980): Alice Notley, Poetry (Winter 1980):Alice Notley(February 17-April 6, 1980): Press Release; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.402)
    - Film (Winter 1980): Bill Lundberg, Film (Winter 1980):Bill Lundberg(February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.403)
    - Sound (Winter 1980): Marilyn Bedford, Includes artist's statement, brochure and press release, contract and background material, including images of prior exhibitions. Sound (Winter 1980):Marilyn Belford "Genetic Messages"(February 17-April 5, 1980): Printed Ephemera; Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.404)
    - Video (Winter 1980): Amy Greenfield, Press materials, with some correspondence and background material. Video (Winter 1980):Amy Greenfield: "The Wave"(February 17-February 22, 1980): Press Release; Art and Event Photographs (Box 17, Folder I.A.405)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Jim Goss, Includes artist's statement, photographs of artworks, contract, and press material. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): Press Release; Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.406)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Alice Adams, Contract and installation photographs. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): Installation Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.407)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Alice Aycock, Contract and description of installation. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.408)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Francesca Jones, Includes brief artist's statement, press release, contract, and installation photograph. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): Press Release; Installation Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.409)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Joseph Kosuth, Contract only. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.410)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): David Diao, Includes postcards and background materials. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): Printed Ephemera (Box 17, Folder I.A.411)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Elizabeth Ewart, Brochure, installation photographs, contract, and some correspondence. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): Installation Photographs; Printed Ephemera; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.412)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): John Fekner, Includes installation image, artist's proposal, and various artist's statements. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): Press Release; Installation Photographs (Box 17, Folder I.A.413)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980):: Russell Maltz, Includes contract, installation photographs, and group exhibition catalogue,Pool, from C.W. Post Campus of Long Island University, New York. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): Installation Photographs (Box 17, Folder I.A.414)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Brenda Miller, Includes press release, installation photographs, postcard, with some correspondence and other materials. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): Installation Photographs; Printed Ephemera; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.415)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Avital Oz, Includes brief artist's statement. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 17, Folder I.A.416)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Lucio Pozzi, Includes postcard (with a detailed project description in lieu of an image), one installation photograph, and contract. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): Installation Photographs; Printed Ephemera; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 18, Folder I.A.417)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Merle Temkin, Includes artist's statement, a sketch by the artist for an installation "specifically for Clocktower Room #3," a drawing with description of the special project, installation photographs and images of previous installations. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): Installation Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 18, Folder I.A.418)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Livio M. Saganic, Includes artist's statement, photographs of previous work, press release, with other materials. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 18, Folder I.A.419)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Judith Simonian, Includes correspondence, project proposal and sketch, with photographs of previous works. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 18, Folder I.A.420)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Barbara Strasen, Includes correspondence, artist's statement and descriptions of the four specific works installed. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 18, Folder I.A.421)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Bill Taggart, Includes artist's statement, with press materials. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 18, Folder I.A.422)
    - Special Projects (Winter 1980): Dennis Oppenheim, 1979-1980; Includes contract, installation photograph, and an unrelated proposal for a Clocktower exhibition from Jeffrey Deitch of politically focused artworks to be titled Abstract Slavery. Special Projects (Winter 1980) (February 17-April 6, 1980): Installation Photographs (Box 18, Folder I.A.423)
    - "Afro-American Abstraction: April Kingsley Curator", 1980; Mainly correspondence. Afro-American Abstraction(February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 18, Folder I.A.424)
    - "Afro-American Abstraction: Travel Information", 1980; Various documents including early descriptions of the exhibitions and press materials. Afro-American Abstraction(February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 18, Folder I.A.425)
    - "Afro-American Abstraction: Artwork Photographs", 1980; Photographs of artworks in previous installations. Afro-American Abstraction(February 17-April 6, 1980): Press Release (Box 18, Folder I.A.426)
    - "Afro-American Abstraction: Checklist", 1980; Afro-American Abstraction(February 17-April 6, 1980): Checklist (Box 18, Folder I.A.427)
    - "Afro-American Abstraction: Artists", 1980; Includes heavily annotated checklist and loan forms. Afro-American Abstraction(February 17-April 6, 1980): Checklist; Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Restricted material removed: Loan forms. (Box 18, Folder I.A.428)
    - "Afro-American Abstraction: Exhibition Space", 1980; Map of installations for the winter season. Afro-American Abstraction(February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 18, Folder I.A.429)
    - "Afro-American Abstraction: Press Releases and Reviews", 1980; News clippings only. Afro-American Abstraction(February 17-April 6, 1980): News Clippings (Box 18, Folder I.A.430)
    - "Afro-American Abstraction: Insurance", 1980; Checklist of insurance valuations, with some correspondence. Afro-American Abstraction(February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 18, Folder I.A.431)
    - "Afro-American Abstraction: Desk Book and Catalogue", 1980-1982; Binder of checklist, photocopied images, and curator's statement for the exhibition; with the 1982 catalogue published by the Art Museum Association, San Francisco, apparently a separate publication from the 1981 P.S. 1 catalogue. Afro-American Abstraction(February 17-April 6, 1980): Printed Ephemera; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 18, Folder I.A.432)
    - Afro-American Abstraction, 1980; Press materials, with some installation sketches and notes. Afro-American Abstraction(February 17-April 6, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 18, Folder I.A.433)
    - The Container Show, 1977; Materials on shipping corporations that would presumably be possible suppliers of shipping containers for this planned (Box 18, Folder I.A.434)
    - "The Container Show: Air Cargo Container Equipment", 1980; Documents pertaining to an unrealized exhibition conceived as artworks displayed inside a series of air cargo containers. (Box 18, Folder I.A.435)
    - "Northwest Council", 1980-1982; Artists' CVs, slides, correspondence, and other material, apparently submitted for consideration through contacts in P.S. 1's Northwest Council of supporters. (Box 18, Folder I.A.436)
    - "Northwest Council", 1980-1982 (Box 18, Folder I.A.437)
    - "Northwest Council", 1980-1982 (Box 19, Folder I.A.438)
    - Sculpture at the Coliseum, 1980; Includes correspondence, floor plans, artists' biographical materials, images of artworks, loan forms, catalogue, and other documents for the exhibition staged in conjunction with the Art Expo NY. The included photographs are those used for the catalogue. Sculpture at the Coliseum(March 5-March 19, 1980): Checklist; Printed Ephemera; Art and Event Photographs; Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Restricted material removed: Loan forms. (Box 716, Folder I.A.439*)
    - Michelangelo Pistoletto: Mirror Painting, 1979-1980; Includes grant materials, press release, notes and background materials, with one letter from the artist. Michelangelo Pistoletto: Mirror Painting(March 10-April 12, 1980): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 19, Folder I.A.440)
    - Jack Roth, 1980; Includes contract, background information, artwork and installation photographs, postcards and press releases. Jack Roth: Ramapo Paintings(March 19-April 12, 1980): Press Release; Installation Photographs; Printed Ephemera; Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 19, Folder I.A.441)
    - John Gillen, 1980; Artist's project description and postcards. John Gillen(April 23-May 17, 1980): Printed Ephemera; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 19, Folder I.A.442)
    - Film as Installation, 1980; Artwork descriptions from many of the artists, sketches and installation details, and loan forms, with some other documentation. Film as Installation(April 23-May 17, 1980): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Loan forms. (Box 19, Folder I.A.443)